Andrew Eisenberg collection of East African commercial sound recordings AD.MC.035
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Series I: Private collector (anonymous) - 78's, circa 1930-1965; 8440; PP; 313 audio_recordings
  - Musa Maruf, 12455
    - Musa Maruf: Katika Duniya, circa 1952-1961; 8620; 1 audio_recording 17.3 MB (Folder 187)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.421, J.R. 772. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:16.
    - Musa Maruf: Mpenzi Wangu Kanitoka, circa 1952-1961; 8709; 1 audio_recording 17.4 MB (Folder 188)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.421, J.R. 773. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:17.
  - Ngoma ya Kilua, 12606
    - Ngoma ya Kilua: Tata Kibondo, circa 1930; 8796; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 189)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.38, W 63266. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:46.
  - Nyameshe Kitoto Adel, 12482
    - Nyameshe Kitoto Adel: Bibi Sofia, N/A; 8566; 1 audio_recording 14.0 MB (Folder 190)
      Serial number: Arrow, ARC.508, ZD. 15. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:38.
    - Nyameshe Kitoto Adel: Ulevi Kubaya, N/A; 8811; 1 audio_recording 14.0 MB (Folder 191)
      Serial number: Arrow, ARC.508, ZD.16. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:39.
  - Nyamwezi Women, 12483
    - Nyamwezi Women with Lugobe: Kwa Mungu kunyenyekea, N/A; 8644; 1 audio_recording 13.7 MB (Folder 192)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1311, XYZ.5099, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:35.
    - Nyamwezi Women with Masudi Bini Amani: Mtemi mfalume wize mpya, N/A; 8714; 1 audio_recording 14.5 MB (Folder 193)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1311, XYZ.5098, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:44.
  - Omar and Party of Charlsea [sic] Club, 12607
    - Omar & Party of Charlsea Club: Wata Ninyamae, N/A; 8827; 1 audio_recording (Folder 194)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2132, CES.4022. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
  - Osman and Party, 12506
    - Osman Juma: Masikini, N/A; 8679; 1 audio_recording 16.6 MB (Folder 195)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2203, CES.1366. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as Osman bin Juma. Duration: 3:08.
    - Osman Juma: Lakchimba, N/A; 8649; 1 audio_recording (Folder 196)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc Serial number: Columbia, EO.2203, CES.1365. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as Osman bin Juma. Duration:.
    - Osman and Party: Hadithiya Baisikli, circa 1956-1959; 8604; 1 audio_recording 17.7 MB (Folder 197)
      Serial number: Tom Tom, TZ.0655, ZD 46, VOM.123. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Title should read: "Hadithi ya Baiskeli." Duration: 3:20.
    - Osman and Party: Hadithiya Moho-Go, circa 1956-1959; 8605; 1 audio_recording 17.1 MB (Folder 198)
      Serial number: Tom Tom, TZ.0654, ZD 45, VOM.124. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Title should read: "Hadithi ya Baiskeli." Duration: 3:14,
  - Osman bin Juma, 12456
    - Osman Bin Juma: Nimepata Kinda, N/A; 8756; 1 audio_recording 15.5 MB (Folder 199)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2143, CES.1091. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:56.
    - Osman Bin Juma: Popote Tufikapo, N/A; 8781; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 200)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2143, CES.1090. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:53.
    - Osman Bin Juma: Mama Njoo Nikwambie Rabai, N/A; 8665; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 201)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2165, CES.1094. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
    - Osman Bin Juma: Ua Langu Limechanua, N/A; 8806; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 202)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2165, CES.1095. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:46.
  - Paulo M. Ojambo and Party, 12484
    - Paulo M. Ojambo & Party: Abalayi Bakhirana, circa 1955-1965; 8547; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 203)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.27, AB 54. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:51.
    - Paulo M. Ojambo & Party: Magumba, circa 1955-1965; 8661; 1 audio_recording 14.9 MB (Folder 204)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.27, AB 53. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:49.
  - Ramadhani Fataki, 12608
    - Ramadhani Fataki with "Ngoma Ya Udi": Shombo binti hasani, N/A; 8788; 1 audio_recording 14.0 MB (Folder 205)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1572, XYZ.6100, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Rajabu Idi (guitar & vocal), Fundi Konde (guitar). Duration: 2:38.
  - Ramathani Hasan, 12485
    - Ramathani Hasan and his guitar: Baba Ananipenda, 8554; 1 audio_recording 14.5 MB (Folder 206)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.127, OAM.184. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:44.
    - Ramathani Hasan and his guitar: Orio Muno, Mama (Thank you very much Mother), 8769; 1 audio_recording 14.9 MB (Folder 207)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.127, OAM 185. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. 7 Duration: 2:48.
  - Rhino Boys, 12486
    - The Rhino Boys: Lipi Uli Pendalo—Walze, N/A; 8650; 1 audio_recording 15.5 MB (Folder 208)
      Serial number: HMV, N.17108, OMC.20183. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Directed and arranged by Jeff Seabrook, vocals by Valentine Muwuiya. Duration: 2:55.
    - The Rhino Boys: Nakupenda—Fox Trot, 8722; 1 audio_recording 15.4 MB (Folder 209)
      Serial number: HMV, N.17108, OMC.20182. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Directed and arranged by Jeff Seabrook, vocals by Valentine Muwuiya. Duration: 2:54.
  - Saleh Buesh, 12457
    - Saleh Buesh: Hadithi ya Sultani na Kitanda Chake Kipya—Sehemu ya Kwanza, circa 1930; 8600; 1 audio_recording 13.2MB (Folder 210)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.9, W.63349. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Part 1 of 4. Duration: 2:47.
    - Saleh Buesh: Hadithi ya Sultani na Kitanda Chake Kipya—Sehemu ya Pili, circa 1930; 8602; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 211)
      Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc Serial number: Columbia, WE.9, W.63350. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Part 2 of 4. Duration: 2:53
    - Saleh Buesh: Hadithi ya Sultani na Kitanda Chake Kipya—Sehemu ya Tatu, circa 1930; 8603; 1 audio_recording 14.6 MB (Folder 213)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.33, W.63351. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Part 3 of 4. Duration: 2:45.
    - Saleh Buesh: Hadithi ya Sultani na Kitanda Chake Kipya—Sehemu ya Nne, circa 1930; 8601; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 212)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.33, W.63352. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Part 4 of 4. Duration: 2:43.
  - Salim and Party, 12609
    - Salim & Party: Mapenzi, N/A; 8670; 1 audio_recording 18.1 MB (Folder 214)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.502, CES.1312. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:24.
  - Salim Zeydani with Arab Men, 12488
    - Salim Zeydani with Arab Men: Alhamdulilla, Hemolo - Side B, 8551; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 215)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1579, XYZ.5617. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:51.
    - Salim Zeydani with Arab Men: Zadal baraa min bayni, N/A; 8839; 1 audio_recording 14.3 MB (Folder 216)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1579, XYZ.5616. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:41.
  - Salum's Brass Band, 12487
    - Salum's Brass Band: Shukurani, N/A; 8789; 1 audio_recording 13.1 MB (Folder 217)
      Serial number: Trek, DC.175, XYZ.6061, RC.31. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader, Salum Seliman. Duration: 2:28.
    - Salum's Brass Band: Twakukumbuka, N/A; 8805; 1 audio_recording 13.4 MB (Folder 218)
      Serial number: Trek, DC.175, XYZ.6062, RC.31. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader, Salum Seliman. Duration: 2:32.
  - Shaban and Party, 12489
    - Shaban & Party: Funga Zizi, circa 1952-1961; 8596; 1 audio_recording 13.8 MB (Folder 219)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.776, J.R. 1555. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:36.
    - Shaban & Party: Natamani Ua, circa 1952-1961; 8732; 1 audio_recording 14.1 MB (Folder 220)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.776, J.R. 1556. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:39.
  - Shahir Sheikh Mohamed Ali (Badi), 12490
    - Shahir Sheikh Mohamad Ali (Badi): Kime Ingiya 1st Part, circa 1930; 8625; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 221)
      Serial number: Pathé, N 73.055, X.79026. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Artist also known as: Mughani Shahir Sheikh Mohamad Ali (Badi). Duration: 2:51.
    - Shahir Sheikh Mohamad Ali (Badi): Kime Ingiya 2nd Part, circa 1930; 8626; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 222)
      Serial number: Pathé, N 73.056, X.79026. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:46.
  - Silas Band, 12491
    - Silas Band: Ewe Mary Wangu, circa 1952-1961; 8591; 1 audio_recording 16.5 MB (Folder 223)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.441, J.R. 902. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Vocalist, S. M. Sururu. Duration: 3:06.
    - Silas Band: Ewe Wangu Rumba, circa 1952-1961; 8593; 1 audio_recording 16.3 MB (Folder 224)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.441, J.R. 903. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Vocalist, S.M. Sururu. Duration: 3:05.
  - Silvano Mukudi, 12492
    - Silvano Mukudi: Sumba Omar, circa 1955-1965; 8701; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 225)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.23, AB 46. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:46.
    - Silvano Mukudi: Paskal Mjomba, circa 1955-1965; 8774; 1 audio_recording (Folder 226)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.23, AB 45. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
  - Siti Binti Saad, 12458
    - Sitti Bint Saad: Manzowea Namapenzi—Rumba Part 1, 8668; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 227)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2006, CES.2012. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Title should read "Mazowea" or "Mazoeya." Alternate spelling of performer is Siti Binti Saad. Duration: 2:47.
    - Sitti Bint Saad: Manzowea Namapenzi—Rumba Part 2, 8669; 1 audio_recording 14.9 MB (Folder 228)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2006, CES 2013. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Title should read "Mazowea" or "Mazoeya." Alternate spelling of performer is Siti Binti Saad. Duration: 2:49.
    - Sitti Bint Saad: Yakini Nuuma—Part I, N/A; 8833; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 229)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2014, CES. 28. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of performer is Siti Binti Saad. Duration: 2:59.
    - Sitti Bint Saad: Yakini Nuuma—Part II, N/A; 8834; 1 audio_recording 15.9 MB (Folder 230)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2014, CES. 29. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of artist's name is Siti Binti Saad. Duration: 2:59.
    - Sitti Bint Saad: Toka Haya Nenda—Rumba, N/A; 8798; 1 audio_recording 14.6 MB (Folder 231)
      Serial number: Columbia, CES.4128. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of artist's name is Siti Binti Saad. Duration: 2:45.
    - Sitti Bint Saad: Pendo Na Kwambia—Part I, 8775; 1 audio_recording 16.0 MB (Folder 232)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2182, CES.19. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of artist's name is Siti Binti Saad. Duration: 3:01.
    - Sitti Bint Saad: Pendo Na Kwambia—Part II, 8776; 1 audio_recording 15.7 MB (Folder 233)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2182, CES.20. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of artist's name is Siti Binti Saad. Duration: 2:58.
    - Sitti Bint Saad: Allahu Ndie Bashiri—Part I, N/A; 8552; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 234)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2190, CES 2008. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of artist's name is Siti Binti Saad. Duration: 2:54.
    - Sitti Bint Saad: Allahu Ndie Bashiri—Part II, N/A; 8553; 1 audio_recording 16.4 MB (Folder 235)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2190, CES 2009. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of artist's name is Siti Binti Saad. Duration: 3:05.
  - Siti Ganduri, 12459
    - Siti Ganduri & Kibwana: Vitendo, 8817; 1 audio_recording 18.6 MB (Folder 236)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.501, CES.1309. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:31.
    - Siti Ganduri & Kibwana: Mtama na Ndege, 8713; 1 audio_recording 18.7 MB (Folder 237)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2172, CES 1310. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:32.
    - Siti Ganduri & Kibwana: Kuku Rumba, 8636; 1 audio_recording 20.8 MB (Folder 238)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2176, CES.1300. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:55.
  - Siti Habu, 12493
    - Siti Habu: Nambiyani, circa 1952-1961; 8726; 1 audio_recording 16.3 MB (Folder 239)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.400, J.R. 405. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:04.
    - Siti Habu: Nenda, circa 1952-1961; 8735; 1 audio_recording (Folder 240)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.400, J.R. 404. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:07.
  - Siti Mary Binti Mabruk, 12507
    - Siti Tete Binti Mabruk: Una Nini Bwana (1st part), circa 1930; 8812; 1 audio_recording 13.9 MB (Folder 241)
      Serial number: Pathé, N 73.017, X.79002. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of artist's name is Mughani Siti Tete Binti Mabruk. Duration: 2:37.
    - Siti Tete Binti Mabruk: Una Nini Bwana (2nd part), circa 1930; 8813; 1 audio_recording 13.5 MB (Folder 242)
      Serial number: Pathé, N 73.018, X.79002. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of artist's name is Mughani Siti Tete Binti Mabruk. Duration: 2:32.
  - Siti Masika, 12460
    - Siti Masika & Sulemani: Mwana Magendo, circa 1955-1965; 8719; 1 audio_recording 15.4 MB (Folder 243)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.16, AB 32. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:54.
    - Siti Masika & Sulemani: Yako Mashakani, circa 1955-1965; 8835; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 244)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.16, AB 31. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
    - Siti Masika & Sulemani & Party: Kuche Chema, circa 1955-1965; 8634; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 245)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.39, AB 78. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
    - Siti Masika & Sulemani & Party: Muhibu Pokea, circa 1955-1965; 8716; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 246)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.39, AB 77. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:53.
  - Siti Tete Binti Mabruk, 12461
    - Siti Tete Binti Mabruk: Tarikiba (1st Part.), circa 1930; 8703; 1 audio_recording 16.8 MB (Folder 247)
      Serial number: Pathé, X 79007. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of artist's name is Mughani Siti Tete Binti Mabruk. Duration: 3:09
    - Siti Tete Binti Mabruk: Tarikiba (2nd Part.), circa 1930; 8704; 1 audio_recording 15.5 MB (Folder 248)
      Serial number: Pathé, X 79007. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Alternate spelling of artist's name is Mughani Siti Tete Binti Mabruk. Duration: 2:55.
  - Stephen & Sisters, 12494
    - Stephen & Sisters: Kwaherini, circa 1955-1956; 8646; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 249)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.252, AB. 503. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Composer, Stephen Ngumbao. Duration: 2:47.
    - Stephen & Sisters: Mmoja Au Wawili, circa 1955-1956; 8705; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 250)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.252, AB. 504. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Composer, Stephen B. Ngumbao. Duration: 2:47.
  - Subeit bin Ambar, 12495
    - Subeit Bin Ambar: Nimeiweka Nadhiri. Part I, circa 1930; 8744; 1 audio_recording 14.9 MB (Folder 251)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.51, W 63169. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:49.
    - Subeit Bin Ambar: Nimeiweka Nadhiri. Part II, circa 1930; 8745; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 252)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.51, W 63170. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
  - Subeti Sunda, 12496
    - Subeti Sunda with Musa Bini Ali: Kwa mtwana Mbaruku, Gonga, 8643; 1 audio_recording 13.6 MB (Folder 253)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1254, WYZ.5073. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:34.
    - Subeti Sunda with Shirazi Men: Aupo tne mkwaju, Tucheze Ponda, 8748; 1 audio_recording 13.6 MB (Folder 254)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1254, XYZ.5075. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:33.
  - Tanganyika Police, Band of, 12497
    - Tanganyika Police, Band of, King's African Rifles: Ngoma, N/A; 8737; 1 audio_recording 12.8 MB (Folder 255)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.59, OAM.161. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Recording is of Regimental March of the 6th Tanganyika Bn., as conducted by Victor Webster. Duration: 2:25.
    - Tanganyika Police, Band of: Mfua Chuma, N/A; 8752; 1 audio_recording 13.5 MB (Folder 256)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.59, OAM.163. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:33.
  - Three Brothers Orchestra, 12498
    - Three Brothers Orchestra: Nalijitahidi Kutengeza Wema, 1955; 8723; 1 audio_recording 13.8 MB (Folder 257)
      Physical charactertistics of original
      Serial number: Trek, DC.177, XYZ.6055, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader of orchestra is A. Othmani. Duration: 2:36.
    - Three Brothers Orchestra: Nimeyasadiki Mahaba, Pumbao, 1955; 8759; 1 audio_recording 16.2 MB (Folder 258)
      Serial number: Trek, DC.177, XYZ.6056, RC.30. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader of orchestra is A. Othmani. Duration: 3:04
  - Uba Binti Sudi, 12462
    - Uba Binti Sudi and Ibina-El-Watani & Party: Simba Tukutane, circa 1952-1961; 8794; 1 audio_recording 16.5 MB (Folder 259)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.184, J.R. 383. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:06.
    - Uba Binti Sudi (sololist) with Ibina-El-Watani & Party: Tuko Mpakani, circa 1952-1961; 8802; 1 audio_recording (Folder 260)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.184, J.R. 382. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:58.
    - Uba Binti Sudi: Halambe, circa 1952-1961; 8749; 1 audio_recording 16.5 MB (Folder 261)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.411, J.R 591. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Includes trumpet by Mohamed Athumani. Duration: 3:06.
    - Uba Binti Sudi: Mutambuwa Mifano, circa 1952-1961; 8754; 1 audio_recording 16.7 MB (Folder 262)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.411, J.R 590. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Includes trumpet by Mohamed Athumani. Duration: 3:09.
  - Umari, 12437
    - Umari: Kisacha—Atar - Side A, N/A; 8630; 1 audio_recording 16.8 MB (Folder 263)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.261, CES. 572. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Part 1 of 2. Duration: 3:10.
    - Umari: Kisacha—Atar - Side B, 8631; 1 audio_recording 16.8 MB (Folder 264)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.261, CES. 573. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Part 2 of 2. Duration: 3:10.
    - Umari: Kisa—Cha—Africa Part 1, N/A; 8628; 1 audio_recording 16.4 MB (Folder 265)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.262, CES. 566. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Part 1 of 2. Duration: 3:06.
    - Umari: Kisa—Cha—Africa Part 2, N/A; 8629; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 266)
      Parts
      Swahili comedy, part 2 of 2.
      Serial number: Columbia, N 73.056, X.79026. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Part 2 of 2. Duration: 2:59.
    - Umari: Ugeni Wa Africa—Part 1, N/A; 8808; 1 audio_recording 16.7 MB (Folder 267)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2004, CES. 570. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:09.
    - Umari: Ugeni Wa Africa—Part 2, N/A; 8809; 1 audio_recording 16.5 MB (Folder 268)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.2004, CES. 571. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:06.
  - Unknown, 12610
    - Unknown recording (Jambo label), 12508; 1 audio_recording 16.9 MB (Folder 269)
      Serial number: unknown, label is degraded and is entirely illegible. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: Unknown.
  - Ustad Omar, 12499
    - Ustad Omar: Vunja Taa Part 1, circa 1952-1961; 8818; 1 audio_recording 17.3 MB (Folder 270)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.233, J.R. 504. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:15.
    - Ustad Omar: Vunja Taa Part 2, circa 1952-1961; 8819; 1 audio_recording (Folder 271)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.233, J.R. 505. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:15.
  - Wamala & Party, 12611
    - Wamala & Party: Chneno, N/A; 8578; 1 audio_recording 18.4 MB (Folder 272)
      Serial number: Columbia, EO.502, CES. 1311. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:28.
  - Yaseen, 12436
    - Yaseen: Natamani Kiss, circa 1956-1959; 8731; 1 audio_recording 16.5 MB (Folder 273)
      Serial number: Tom Tom, TR.466, T 0886. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Composer of melody identified as Farid el Atrash. Duration: 3:06.
    - Yaseen (Radio Singer): Natugane, circa 1956-1959; 8733; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 274)
      Serial number: Tom Tom, TR.466, T 0887. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Composer of melody identified as Farid el Atrash. Duration: 2:58.
  - Yaseen and Kasanga, 12509
    - Yaseen & Kasanga Party: Jambo Jambo Bugi, 1955-1956; 8612; 1 audio_recording 16.3 MB (Folder 275)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.11, CES. 10016. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 3:05.
    - Yaseen & Kasanga Party: Wazimu—Samba, 1955-1956; 8828; 1 audio_recording 16.3 (Folder 276)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.11, CES. 10015. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 3:05.
    - Yaseen & Kasanga Party: Kopa Nakulipa, 1955-1956; 8633; 1 audio_recording 17.5 MB (Folder 277)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.12, CES. 10018. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 3:18.
    - Yaseen & Kasanga Party: Nita Kula Sumu, 1955-1956; 8762; 1 audio_recording 17.1 MB (Folder 278)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.12, CES. 10017. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Duration: 3:14.
    - Yaseen Party & Kasanga: Nasikitika, 1955-1956; 8730; 1 audio_recording (Folder 279)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.17, CES. 10029. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Accompanied by Kasanga Yaseen Orchestra. Duration: 2:54.
    - Yaseen Party & Kasanga: Shibu Mwairo, 1955-1956; 8786; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 280)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM. 17, CES. 10028. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Accompanied by Kasanga Yaseen Orchestra. Duration: 2:59.
    - Yaseen Party & Kasanga: Kalipso—Swahili, 1955-1956; 8619; 1 audio_recording 15.7 MB (Folder 281)
      Serial number: Columbia, EOM.18, CES. 10031. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Singer also known as: Yaseen Mohamed, Yasseen Mohamed, Yaseen Tofaly. Accompanied by Kasanga Yaseen Orchestra. Duration: 2:58.
  - Yaseen and King's Band, 12510
    - Yaseen and King's Band: Nampenda Mpenzi, circa 1952-1961; 8727; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 282)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.758, A.M. 14. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:58.